《黑镜》
- 利亚姆·福克斯韦尔 欢迎 - 谢谢
- Liam Foxwell, welcome. - Thank you.
好了 我有点话要说
OK, little speech time.
我对每一个被评估的人都说过
I've mentioned this to everyone about their appraisals,
我希望你也明白
and I just want you to know that.
评估不是对冗余人员的迫害
this isn't a witch-hunt for the deadwood.
它更像是
It is much more of a…
淘金
treasure hunt for the gold?
坏东西沉下去了
Shit sinks.
但同时 精华浮上来
But also, cream floats.
是 我明白
Yes, yes, I see that.
我们正在开拓的新领域
A new the area we're getting lots of play in …
同时也是你将负责的主要工作
and your office could be at the centre for …
是那些过往的关于父母教育问题的诉讼
is litigation in retrospective parenting cases.
过往的父母教育问题诉讼？
Retrospective…
对 警察状告父母 因为他们对管教孩子不上心
Bobby sues Mum and Dad for insufficient attention.
这会导致自信缺乏 收入困难
leading to lack of confidence, leading to damages against earnings.
我没问题 公司也安排好了吗？我是说在伦理上
Right, and we're OK, the firm's OK with that, ethically?
和道德上？
And morally?
是的
Yeah.
当然
Sure.
是 是 好的
Yeah, yeah, right.
那你呢？
Are you?
完全没问题
Totally, yeah.
是的
Yes.
好的 利亚姆 听着
OK, Liam, look,
如果我们邀请你加入我们在新环境中的公司
so if we invite you to stay with the firm in the new environment,
我们需要你做一个关于你个人的详尽的回放
what we'd have you do is pull an exhaustive redo.
可能 就在下周
with personnel, maybe… next week.
我现在就能做详细回放 只是
Well, I was ready to do a big redo right now, but…
不用 下周吧
No, it's fine, next week's fine.
但我需要知道的是
But I have to ask you this …
你要放心他们不会做出
they're not going to hit anything.
什么很出格的事 是吧？
to freak us out, are they?
你在这一季度里没有对记忆进行重大删除吧？
There's no major deletions this quarter?
没有没有 都在可删除的参数范围以内
No, no, everything's well within… parameters.
太棒了 利亚姆 这真是太好了
Great, OK, Liam, this has been really great.
真心希望 期待着再次见到你
Look, really hope to… look forward to seeing you again.
好的 谢谢
OK, thank you.
《你的人生》
去机场 谢谢
Airport, please.
活着的
Live…
呼吸着的
breathe…
附有气味的
smell.
全面光谱记忆
Full-spectrum memory.
现在你可以升级你的记忆芯片
You can get a willow grain upgrade for less than the price.
比买一杯咖啡更优惠的价格
of a daily cup of coffee,
享受三十年免费售后服务
and three decades of backup for free.
局部麻醉后 再牢固的镶嵌进体内
In-store ingrain procedure with local anaesthetic…
然后就能轻松离开了
and you're good to go.
因为记忆是为了生活
Because memory is for living.
太棒了 利亚姆 这真是太好了
OK, great, this has been really great, Liam,
真心希望 期待能再次见到你
we really hope to… look forward to seeing you again.
We really hope to… look forward to seeing you again.
抱歉！
Sorry!
福克斯韦尔先生
Mr Foxwell.
你能回放你最近24小时的记录吗？
Could you just rewind me your last 24 hours for me, please?
好的 请用64倍速回放一周的景象
Great, and back that up for me times 64 for the week.
很好
That's great.
旅途愉快！
Enjoy your flight, Mr Foxwell.
我不是在说笑 好吧？但你看那个
I'm not being funny, right, but look at that.
看什么？
Look at what?
那个！磨损了的地毯 那儿 看见没？
That! Frayed carpet, there, you see?
- 你是认真的吗？- 是 认真的
- Seriously? - Yes, seriously!
这是个五星级套房！
This is a five-star suite.
我花了这么多钱 就应该有完美的细节
I pay good money to have perfect details.
现在 这破地毯将会伴随着我一生的记忆
Now I've got that shitty carpet for the rest of my life.
如果你一直盯着它的话就会
Only if you keep looking at it, mate.
真是谢谢你 乔纳斯！
Thanks, Jonas!
滚吧你
Fuck off.
好吧 现在你觉得这地毯糟透了
All right, now, you thought the carpet was bad,
但再看看这个
have a look at this.
你已经见过露西了 在都柏林的婚礼上？
You've met Lucy, my wife, at the Dublin wedding?
对 嗨 利亚姆
That's right, yes, hi, Liam.
再嗨一次
Hi… Hi again.
你好
Hello.
露西 我是利亚姆 在都柏林的婚礼上见过
Lucy … Liam, we met at the Dublin wedding.
利亚姆！
Liam!
太棒了
Great.
- 利亚姆 对 请进 - 谢谢
- Liam, yes. Come in. - Thank you.
- 很高兴再次见到你 - 我也是
- Great to see you again. - Yeah, you too.
斐在哪？她躲着你吗？
Where's Fi been hiding you?
你知道的 她在家里
You know, in our house.
我们不知道
We didn't know … well,
她不知道你到底能不能来
she didn't know if you would make it.
它结束得比我想象的早
It was over quicker than I thought.
不好意思 你好！
Sorry, hello.
喝点什么？啤酒？
Let's get you a drink. Beer OK?
好的 谢谢你
Lovely, thank you.
他们都在那边 我一会就来
Everyone's through there, so I'll be in in a minute,
- 好吗？- 好的 谢谢
- OK? - OK, thank you.
你提前回来了 我还以为你来不了
You're back early, then, I didn't think you'd make it.
对 我没留下来过夜
Yeah, I didn't stay over…
搭了早一点的班机 所以
and I caught an early flight back, so…
- 嗨 - 你好
- Hi. - Hello.
对你的评估怎么样？
So, how was the appraisal?
他们说要我做一个回放 在下周 所以
Well, they said they'd let me do a redo sometime next week, so…
但他们对你评价很好？
But good?
嗯…
Well…
- 稍后再说？- 稍后再说
- Later? - Later.
小宝贝朱迪怎么样？
How's Jody?
在家 吉娜在照看她
At home, Gina's babysitting.
乔纳斯 这位是
Jonas, this is…
- 我叫利亚姆 - 我是乔纳斯
- Liam … - Jonas.
很高兴见到你 兄弟
Dude, it's really nice to meet you.
- 你好吗？- 很好 谢谢
- You all right? - Good, thank you.
- 你认识杰夫的 - 是的
- And you know Jeff? - Yes.
你会记得我和杰夫是因为他给你看过
Yeah, you remember meeting Jeff, because he'd have shown you,
关于他电冰箱的侧面的一个回放
I don't know, a redo of the side of his fridge.
是啊 滚远点 乔纳斯
Yeah, yeah, yeah, piss off, Jonas.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
你妻子今晚对我坏极了
Your wife's being very mean to me tonight.
她一向如此
Well she's like that.
是吗 告诉我
Yeah, tell me about it.
- 还要酒吗？- 不用了 谢谢 乔纳斯
- You all right for a drink? - I'm fine, thank you, Jonas.
林恩 过来见见利亚姆 他是
Lynn, come and meet Liam, he's…
一个马上就没人雇也不值得雇的律师
A soon-to-be unemployed/unemployable lawyer.
这是杰夫
And Jeff.
杰夫和斐
Jeff and Fi…
过去经常跟我和保罗一起在弗雷泽开派对
used to run the parties down the Fraser Road with Paul and me.
疯狂的旧时光啊
Mad old days.
那是在我们创办Kings以前
Before we started up the Kings.
这样…
So, yeah…
那利亚姆 你是去了一个估价会议？
So, Liam, what was it you had, an assessment?
评估会议
Appraisal.
怎么样？
How'd it go?
还不错
Good.
你知道 简直是个灾难
Well, it was a disaster,
但你知道 我也不知道结果
but you know, I don't know.
- 难以揣测？- 对
- Hard to gauge? - Yeah.
那展示给我们看看
Let's have a look.
回放 我们可以评估一下他们的评估
Redo, we can appraise the appraisal.
行 好
Yeah, great.
投影到那上面 我们来给你评分
Throw it up there and we can grade you.
来吧！
Come on…
这会很有趣 我们可以
It could be fun, we could…
投票！
vote!
- 保罗 - 怎么了？
- Paul? - Yeah?
我在招募处工作 所以我的意见或许有用
I work in recruitment, so it might be quite useful for you.
对 好吧
Right, OK.
利亚姆准备回放他的评估会 我们来给他打分
Liam's redoing his appraisal so we can give him marks.
- 作批注 - 给指示
- Notes. - Pointers, you know.
- 我想利亚姆可能 - 是 你知道吗
- I think Liam would probably… - Yes, do you know what…
大家 别这样 说真的 这不好
Guys, no, come on, seriously, that's not cool,
我的意思是 利亚姆明显觉得这不太舒服
I mean Liam's obviously uncomfortable,
所以 我们别提它了 行吗？
so let's just drop it, yeah?
希望你玩得愉快
Have a cool time.
该吃饭了！
Time to eat!
饭已经好了
It's ready.
谢谢你邀请我们
Thank you so much for inviting us this evening.
好久没聚过了 好久了
It's been too long, too long.
斐
Fi.
乔纳斯 我以前没见过他 对吗？
I haven't met him before, have I? Jonas, is it?
他是原来的老朋友之一
He's one of the old crowd.
我想我已经告诉过你了
I think I said.
- 你还好吧？- 挺好
- You OK? - Yeah, yeah.
- 如果你没心情 我们可以离开 - 不用
- You know, if you're not in the mood, we can go. - No, no.
- 确定？- 我很好
- I'm fine. - Sure?
对 我带的足够多
Yeah! I brought enough for others to share.
- 谢谢 - 分手后我就经常自己煮饭
- Thank you. - I've, been cooking a lot since the break-up.
乔纳斯有段不幸福的婚姻
Jonas has had a tough one.
感觉很糟糕吧？
Was it bad?
对
Yeah.
我们正在筹备婚礼
Yeah, we were in the middle of planning is all.
我突然意识到如果这段婚礼对你来说意义越小
and I suddenly realised that the less the relationship means.
你就会越重视婚礼这个形式
the more you spend on the wedding, you know!
你开始挑剔每个细节
You actually start obsessing over the tiniest little details,
比如请柬的的纸要多厚才合适
like the thickness of the wedding invitation paper.
因为 我是说 上帝才知道
because, I mean, God knows…
你需要一些可供谈论的话题
you need something to fucking talk about!
大家 这是海伦
So, everybody, this is Helen.
这是乔纳斯
Helen, Jonas.
这是大家！
And everyone!
- 嗨 - 请随意
- Hi! - Help yourself.
乔纳斯正在说明为什么婚姻是个骗子
Jonas was just explaining why relationships are a sham.
是骗子吗？太糟了！
Are they? Shit!
就好像你们去剧院
They're like going to the theatre, OK?
花了很多钱买票
You pay loads to go…
但最后却发现这完全是浪费
and ultimately you are wasting your entire night,
但当有人问你们好看吗？
so, when someone asks you, "Did you have a good time?",
却都说当然 当然 太棒了
you both say, "Yeah! Yeah, it was great."
所以问题就是你花费的越多
The problem is the more that you pay.
关系持续时间越长
and the longer it goes on,
更多的当然 我们很喜欢就会出现
the more you're, "Yeah, we loved it!",
「我们喜欢在一起 不上其他任何人」
you know, "We love being together and never fucking anyone else"
一生中 能有个人与你分享
"and only just having one other person"
彼此真正的想法 太棒了！
"to share our real thoughts with for our entire lives, yeah, it's great!"
这样来说 你有爱过她吗？
Would you say you loved her, though?
我只能说我们真的喜欢对方 就是这样
I just think we just really fancied each other and that was what it was.
你知道最开始我们是怎么样的
You know what it's like early on.
你知道我们就是
You know, we were just, I don't know,
就是两个在工具箱里的工具
we were just two tools in the tool shed.
刚好彼此合适罢了 正他妈的合适！
that just fit together really fucking well.
到最后的时候 我们就像是这样：
I mean, still, by the end, I'd be like,
亲爱的 你上去睡觉吧
"Go on, honey, you go up, "
我还想再看一下新闻
"I'm just going to watch a little bit more of the news"
然后我其实是在看
and I'd find myself, you know, watching redos of, like,
我早年激情四射时的记忆回放
hot times in earlier relationships!
淡定！
Easy!
我想说 有一个漂亮女人正在楼上
I'm just saying, there's a beautiful woman upstairs,
等着和我做爱
you know, waiting to have sex with me.
什么 现在就有？
What, right now?
她就在楼上 等着和我缠绵
She's upstairs, you know, waiting to have sex with me.
我却坐在楼下 回放那些激情时刻
and I'm sat downstairs watching redos of, like, some hot times.
和那些我都不知道在哪搭上的女孩的激情时刻
with some hot girl that I just picked up in some place.
我真是太圆满了！说真的 太圆满了
and I'm fucking pulling myself off. I mean, seriously?
别这表情
Come on…
别这样 兄弟们
Come on, guys.
我们都有记忆芯片
I mean, we all scroll through the Grain.
回味我们最激情的时光
rifling through our greatest hits.
满足我们偶尔的肮脏小思想 当然要如此
for a little bit of filth now and then, surely?
我不会
Not me.
海伦没装记忆芯片
Helen doesn't have a Grain!
不会吧！
No shit!
因为政治原因吗？
Was that a political thing?
不 不 12个月前 它被盗走了
No, no, I was gouged about 12 months ago.
天哪！痛吗
Jesus, was that painful?
非常痛
Total agony.
但在疼痛作用下 我其实不记得有多痛了
But on the plus of that, I don't remember it that clearly.
现在这里留了一个疤
There's a scar on here.
我能看一下吗？
Yeah, can I…?
这感觉起来还不错
Yeah, that feels quite nice.
对脑部没伤害 绝对没有
Yeah, no brain damage, clearly!
我还能看得很清楚 所以没影响
Well, my sight held on fine, so…
那么 谁偷走了？
So, who took it then?
有人下了订单要买它 警察查出了
Stolen to order, as far as they could tell,
或许卖给那些中国百万富翁
probably to some millionaire Chinese perve.
- 真的吗？- 真的
- Really?! - Yeah.
这是真的吗？
Is that for real?
是的 里面所有记忆都没加密
Yeah, and none of it was encrypted, so…
所以 全被看见了！
So, they saw the lot!
被盗以后 我过了几天没有记忆芯片的日子
The thing is, after I was gouged I didn't have one for a few days.
我有几分喜欢那种日子！
and then just kind of, liked it.
这很酷
It's cool.
是很酷
That's cool.
我的意思是 因为越来越多人
I mean, because more people are…
我是说现在 选择摘掉记忆芯片
I mean, now, right? Like, going Grainless?
我敢说大部分都是妓女
I believe it's huge with hookers.
我无意冒犯！
I mean, no offence!
不 没事 没关系 当然 我
No, no, it's OK. Sure, I…
我也觉得只约会一个男人很无聊
Well, I'm pretty boring. One man is a time.
终身一夫一妻制
Serial monogamist.
我就是一夫一妻制
I'm a serial monogamist.
我是说我现在对我的玉米条很忠诚！
I'm staying faithful to my cornflakes right now!
我想 这是个很有趣的选择 摘掉芯片
Well, I think it's an interesting choice, going Grainless.
是个勇敢的选择
It's a brave choice.
我很抱歉 但我
I'm sorry, but I…
我绝不会这么做
I couldn't do it.
我打算回放一下在弗雷泽O的时光
OK, I was going to play some redos from the Fraser O days.
在那的最后一晚 压抑但有趣
Stuff from last night, depressing and fun.
你知道吗 一半的自然记忆都是垃圾
You know half the organic memories you have a junk,
不可信
just not trustworthy.
科琳 在芯片开发部工作
Colleen works in Grain development.
世界上一半的人 都会被引导产生错误记忆
With half the population you can implant false memories,
你需要做的只是问他们一些引导性的问题
just by asking leading questions in therapy.
比如你可以让他们以为曾在某个商场迷过路
You can make people remember getting lost.
其实他们根本没去过那个商场
in shopping malls they never visited,
或者说为恋童癖的保姆感到烦恼
getting bothered by paedophile babysitters.
其实你根本没有保姆
they never had.
我只是觉得现在比较快乐
I'm just happier now.
太棒了 利亚姆 这真是太好了
OK, great, Liam, this has been, this has been really great…
我们真的希望 期待着再次见到你！
we really hope to look forward to seeing you again.
他期待再次见到你 这很好
He looks forward to seeing you again, that's good.
希望期待着能再次见到你
"Hopes" to look forward.
我们真心希望期待着能再次见到你
We really hope to look forward to seeing you again.
他只是说场面话
It's phoney.
等一下
Hang on.
暂停
Pause it.
往回倒一点
Now backup.
放大
Zoom in there.
看到没 那是个勾
Come on, that's a tick.
也可能是V或者L
That could be a V or an L.
- 是勾！- 还可能是卍的第一笔呢！
- It's a tick! - Or the start of the swastika.
很有可能是卍的第一笔 他们都是些怪胎！
It's probably the start of the swastika, they were such pricks!
- 和老朋友在一起 开心吗？- 当然
- Did you have fun with the old gang? - Yeah.
你和乔纳斯聊了很多吗？
D'you speak to that Jonas much?
不 并没有
No, no, not really.
他是个二货 是吧？
He's a bit of a knob, ain't he?
有点傻逼
Bit of a dick?
乔纳斯
Jonas.
一直在搞弄他的那些婚姻论
Pulling himself off to his own relationship theories.
这真令人厌烦 他一直在散布那些婚姻论
It must be such a drag, Jonas, putting it about!
当他帮我解围的时候
And when he protected me from those arseholes,
嘿 别这样
"Hey, come on, guys, "
让人回放评估这事不太好 兄弟们
"it's really not cool to redo another man's appraisals, dudes."
那你为什么邀请他来家里
Then why invite him over?
我喜欢他
I like him.
而且是你想我邀请他
You wanted me to invite him.
我可什么都没说
I didn't say anything.
他说什么你都很捧场
You were laughing at everything he said.
你邀请他的！
You invited him!
很明显 其实我不想要他来
It was obvious I didn't want him to come.
好早 现在还很早
It's only, it's early to call it a night.
想找个酒吧喝点酒吗？
Do fancy a quick one down the pub?
我们必须回去了
We've got to get back,
去把我们的小宝贝朱迪从恋童癖的保姆手上救出来！
rescue Jodie from the paedophile babysitter!
对
Yeah.
你为什么不来我们家呢？
But why don't you come back to ours,
喝点夜啤酒什么的？
for a nightcap if you want?
看见了？
See?
很明显我其实不想他来
It was obvious I didn't want him to come,
只想礼貌性的问一下那个呆瓜
I was being polite to a moron.
如果你真的不想 你可以把他弄走
If you really don't want to come, you can get rid of him.
那个 现在几点了？
Well, actually, what time is it?
午夜了
It's midnight.
都已经这么晚了 时间过得真快
Shit, it's quite late, time's gone on.
是啊 时间不等人
Yeah, time does that.
居然这么快就过了15分钟了
15 minutes.
对
Yeah.
我们保姆还在家里 所以…
But we've got the babysitter inside, so…
有新情况？
So, is that new info?
不 我们只是认为她应该还在 对吧 斐？
No, it's just that we, I mean, we thought, right, Fi?
- 对 - 对
- Yeah. - Yeah.
噢 我知道了
OK, no, I get it.
其实是 因为我们都非常累了
No, it's just that, actually, it turns out we're tired.
所以把保姆在的事儿给忘了 突然想起来 所以
and I guess we forgot, but now we've remembered, so…
不好意思
Sorry.
不 没事 真的
No, it's fine, really.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事 别担心
It's cool, no worries.
我还有后备计划呢！所以
I've got a back-up plan, so…
对 太好了 我们支持你的后备计划
Cool, well, we vote the back-up.
我就去了
Yeah, I will do.
回见 斐
See you later, Fi.
认识你很高兴
It was good to meet you, man.
我也是
Yeah.
相处很愉快
Nice one.
太好了 太妙了
Brilliant. Brilliant.
好 呵呵
OK, cool.
认识你真高兴！
Good to meet you, man.
是的
Yeah.
吉娜 等出租车要40分钟
Listen, Gina, it's a 40-minute wait for a cab, but if you want,
我的办公房里有铺好的床 你可以留下来休息
I have the bed made up in my office.
好的 谢谢了
OK, thanks, Fi.
要用什么就拿 有T恤还有
Hey, there's just, you know, use anything. There's T-shirts and…
好的 谢谢 我会的
Yeah, thanks, I'll show myself out.
- 好的 - 你们晚安
- All right. - Night, guys.
你们晚安
Night, guys.
晚安 吉娜
Night, Gina.
谢谢
Thank you.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
爱你 爱你
Love you, love you.
他是你们朋友中的中心人物吗？
Was he a big part of the gang?
- 谁？- 乔纳斯！
- Who? - Jonas?
我不知道 怎么了？
I don't know, yeah?
我想 他一定经常在女孩身边打转
Let me guess, he'd spent his time oozing round the girls,
- 献殷勤什么的 - 不清楚
- offering backrubs. - Not really.
然后再乘机下手
Circling for an orifice.
他是一直这么油腔滑调还是
Was he always that oily or…
听着
OK, look.
什么？
What?
其实没什么 只是
It's nothing, but…
你可能也察觉到了 就是
You may have noticed a bit of an atmosphere because…
几年前 我和乔纳斯曾经约会过
me and Jonas, years ago, had a bit of a thing.
你和那个油腻男约会过？
You had a thing with oily dude man?
这又不是什么大不了的事！
It was just a little thing.
我甚至都不知道你那时回来发展了 所以
and I didn't even know you back then, so…
你和他睡过了？
You slept with oily dude man?
这真是太滑稽了
That's hilarious!
那你和姬玛呢？
We've all got our skeletons, how about you and Gemma?
什么？我和你说过姬玛！
What, I told you about Gemma.
她是个疯子！
Gemma was a nutcase…
但你从没提过乔纳斯
But you never mentioned Jonas.
我说过 我告诉过你
I did, I told you…
我在马拉喀什的时候和一个男人约会过
I hooked up with someone in Marrakech.
- 他就是马拉喀什那个？- 这是我做的蠢事
- Jonas is Mr Marrakesh?! - It was a stupid thing…
我本以为马拉喀什那男的会是个超级有魅力的
I thought Mr Marrakech was some sort of super cool…
反正不是他这种
Not him.
这都过了好多年了 再说
It was years ago and…
你会因为这事很窘迫吗？
Are you embarrassed by that?
因为这的确让人尴尬！
Cos it's embarrassing.
不好意思 但你尴尬吗？
I'm sorry, but, Christ, are you not embarrassed?
这是很多年前的事了
It was years ago.
所以你和他约会了一个月？
But you dated him for a month?
我是这么说的
That's what I said.
但当时你和我说马拉喀什的时候
Cos when you told me about Mr Marrakech,
说的是一星期
it was a week.
没 我没有
No, I didn't.
那你呢？
What about you?
我现在不想看我们的第一次！
I don't want to see our first time right now.
你马上要说话了
Syou're about to talk.
我离开了 头脑发热的了一阵
I went away and had a little thing that did my head in for a while.
和一个一个
with this, sort of…
和一个在马拉喀什的傻子在一起了一段时间
this, sort of, headfuck that I met in Marrakech.
马拉喀什先生？
Mr Marrakech?
对 可以这么叫
Yeah.
我在想 他一定有一个大钢炮
I'm imagining a chillum and a big knob.
不 其实是小牙刷
No, it was like dormouse.
这段感情对你来说重要吗 伤透了心？
Big deal, big heart-breaker?
没有 才一个星期而已
No, it was just a week.
怪异的一个星期
It was a weird week.
一星期还是一个月？
So, a weird week or a month?
重点是 这段感情不是那么重要
The point is, it wasn't a big deal.
足够重要了 让你头脑发热
Well, it was big enough to do your head in.
乔纳斯 马拉喀什的微型小鸡鸡让你头脑发热了！
Jonas, King Dormouse-Dick of Marrakech did your head in!
本来那是个很美好的夜晚 至少曾经是
That was a nice night, used to be.
你死磕上了！
You're getting obsessed.
- 我没有 - 你原来对丹的事也这样
- I'm not. - We had all this with Dan,
我希望你别再这么做了
I don't want you going like that again.
丹他有一双惊悚的水泡小眼睛 他还经常
He had little creepy beady eyes and he was always…
怎么？表现得好像他自己很有趣？
What? Acting like he was interested?
你知道吗 我觉得他可能的确喜欢我！
And you know what, I think he probably did fancy me.
而且他哪有那么可怕
and actually he wasn't completely hideous,
就算有时候是很可怕
so in another life I don't know,
但我和他之间没什么
but nothing happened!
至于乔纳斯
And Jonas…
他是我的前炮友 那又怎么了？
he's an old fling. So what?
别扯在一起说！
Don't go all fucked up!
- 什么？我搞砸的？- 不 我的意思是…
- What, I'm fucked up, am I? - No, I mean, just…
说的太妙了 有时你真他妈是个婊子！
No, no, no, that's brilliant, sometimes you're a bitch.
我不是认真的
I didn't mean that.
你是个婊子！
You're a bitch!
我希望你把它删了
I'd like you to erase that.
你是个婊子！
You're a bitch!
前面还说了「有时候」
Also, "sometimes".
你不能断章取义！
You can't just edit off the word, "sometimes"!
对不起 斐
I'm sorry, Fi,
我知道有时候自己像个蠢货又情绪无常
I know I go a bit weird and wonky sometimes.
- 我爱你 你知道的 - 我知道
- I love you, you know? - I know.
在工具箱里的工具刚好彼此合适罢了
in a toolshed that just fit together really fucking well,
我们就像是这样：
but still by the end I'd be like,
亲爱的 上去睡觉吧
"Go, on, you go to bed, honey,
我还想再看一下新闻
"I'm just going to catch a little bit more of the news, "
其实我是在看…
and then I'd find myself, you know, watching redos of hot times…
早年激情四射时的记忆回放
in earlier relationships.
有一个漂亮女人正在楼上
I've got a beautiful woman upstairs waiting to have sex with me.
然后我其实是在看
And I'd find myself, you know, watching redos of…
我早年激情四射时的记忆回放
hot times in earlier relationships.
淡定！
Easy!
唇语读取重现功能已激活
Lip read reconstruction enabled.
- 见到你很高兴 - 我也是
- Hey, it's good to see you. - Good to see you, too.
听到说你要来的时候我还很紧张
I was nervous when I heard you were going to be here.
这有点怪异 不是吗
It's weird, isn't it?
- 早安 - 吉娜 来这边
- Morning. - Gina, over here.
过来一下 我需要你的意见
Come here a second. I just want your opinion.
我在做点傻事
It's just a silly game.
坐下吧
Sit down.
回答这个
Answer this.
我就是一夫一妻制
I'm a serial monogamist.
我是说我现在对我的玉米条很忠诚！
I'm staying faithful to my corn flakes right now.
你觉得 好笑吗？
Now, is that funny?
你不需要说好话 这人是个傻逼
There's no need to be nice, the man's a prick.
你觉得这好笑吗？
Is that funny, in your opinion?
这个…
Well…
我就是一夫一妻制
I'm a serial monogamist.
我是说我现在对我的玉米条很忠诚！
I'm staying faithful to my corn flakes right now.
- 不好笑？- 不好笑
- No? - No.
- 我不知道 - 你知道的
- I don't know. - You do.
早安
Morning.
这是什么？
What's this?
我只是再问吉娜对此的意见
I'm just getting Gina's opinion on something.
我是一夫一妻制者
I'm a serial monogamist.
我是说我现在对我的玉米条很忠诚！
I'm staying faithful to my corn flakes right now.
我会有疑问是因为你觉得这很好笑
I was just wondering because you found it funny,
但其实不好笑 吉娜也这么觉得
but it isn't, and Gina agrees.
我真的不想卷进来
I don't really want to get involved.
- 帮你叫个出租车吧 - 我爸快来了
- Let me get you a cab. - My dad's on his way.
只还需要问你一件事
Just one other thing.
我们都想他来
We both want him to come back,
但谁更想他来？
but who wants him to come back more?
认真思考一下
In your opinion, off the top of your head,
你认为谁更想他来？
who wants him to come back more?
好的 拜拜
OK, well, bye.
拜拜
Yeah, bye.
好早 现在还很早
It's early. It's early to call it a night.
你想找个酒吧喝一杯吗？
Fancy a quick one down the pub?
我们得回去
Got to get back,
把小宝贝朱迪从恋童癖的保姆手上救出来！
rescue Jodie from the paedophile baby-sitter.
这只是个 只是个玩笑
That's just a… That's a joke.
对不起
Sorry.
乔纳斯 为什么不来我们家
Jonas, why don't you come back to ours…
喝点啤酒什么的？
for a nightcap, if you want?
好啊
Yeah.
别在意这个玩笑 谁更想他来？
Now, ignore the joke. Who's more keen for him to come back?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道的 吉娜
You do know, Gina.
不好意思 他酒还没醒
I'm so sorry, he's really hungover.
没关系的
That's OK.
我是说我现在对我的玉米条很忠诚！
I'm staying faithful to my corn flakes right now.
客观来说 这一点也不好笑
That is just objectively not funny.
谁都会说这并不好笑
Anyone would say, "That's not funny."
这他妈太让人尴尬了
That was fucking embarrassing.
不管你还要干什么 停止！
Whatever you're queuing up, stop it.
坐下 来吧
Sit down, please.
你看见了没？
You see that?
你认识杰夫的
You know Geoff?
你会记得我和杰夫是因为他给你看过
Yeah, you remember me and Geoff, because he would have shown you.
关于他电冰箱侧面的一个回放 诸如此类
a re-do of the side of his fridge, something like that.
- 说说有什么不同 - 你醉了
- Spot the difference. - You're drunk.
我就是那个不同
I'm the difference.
你对待他时 好像他是世界上最好的人
He's the greatest guy in the world.
我一来 你就沉默了
and then I arrived and… you clam.
再看一次
For clarity.
我们那时只是在说话
We're just talking!
对 但就在几秒钟后 你一下子僵住了
But moments later, you're so stiff.
我不知道 一个
I don't know, a re-do…
你都不知道该怎么呆在他周围
You don't know how to stand around him.
你一直在计量着 表现也忽冷忽热
Your gauges are all over the place, hot and cold.
这太蠢了！
This is just stupid!
你掩饰不了 至少不能完全
You can't hide it. Not completely.
看看你是怎么看着他的
See how you look at him.
如果这段婚礼对你来说意义越小
The less the relationship means,
你就会越重视婚礼这个形式
the more you spend on the wedding.
你开始挑剔每个细节
Really, you start obsessing about these tiny little details.
比如请柬的的纸要多厚才合适
like the thickness of the wedding invitation paper.
看你是怎么看着我的
Now, how you look at me.
这是个很有趣的选择 摘掉芯片
I think it's an interesting choice, going grainless.
是个勇敢的选择
It's a brave choice.
不好意思 但是
I'm sorry, but…
说你其实是像看他那样看着我 你说不出口
Tell me you look at me nice like you look at him. You can't.
那我是怎样看着你的呢 利亚姆？
And how am I looking at you now, Liam?
你到底和他在一起了多久？
How long did you go out with him for?
这很重要吗？
Does it matter?
你知道吗？一半的自然记忆都是垃圾
You know, half the organic memories you have are junk.
不可信 当遇到小事
Just not trustworthy. When it comes to little things.
和大事
And big ones.
这是在马拉喀什吗？
Is that Marrakesh?
这看起来像是在马拉喀什吗？
Does that look like Marrakesh?
不！
No.
这不是在马拉喀什
It's not Marrakesh.
所以 你和他在一起有多久了？
So, how long did you go out with him for?
好吧 大约6个月
All right, about six months.
所以不是一星期或者一个月 而是6个月
So not a week or a month. Six months.
还真是永不消逝的电波
The ever-inflating romance.
你可能现在还和他搞着呢！
You're probably still going out with him.
我为什么要在这里接受你的拷问？
Why am I on trial here?
现在你和他是怎么回事？
What's been going on?
我现在和他没什么事！
Nothing has been going on.
只是… 你知道是什么样的 和一个人上床
It was… Christ, you know how it is when you first get with someone.
前男友的问题就会跑出来
and then previous boyfriends come up.
他不是什么男朋友 他是你所说的怪异一星期
He was never a boyfriend, he was always a weird week.
我根本不看重 所以我蒙混过去了 它只是
I downplayed it. I fudged it, it was…
你撒谎了
You lied.
不是所有的事情都撒谎 利亚姆
Not everything that isn't true is a lie, Liam.
- 你在说什么？- 好吧
- Hello? - Yeah, allright!
和他在一起是比我原先说的长久
So he was a bigger thing than I made out and,
还有 他是有点傻
yeah, he's sort of a dick.
有点？他是个巨傻
Sort of? He's a massive…
我那时喜欢着他
I liked him then.
现在不喜欢了
And I don't like him,
我是指 不是情人那种喜欢了
not like that, not now.
让我们把事情搞清楚
So, just to get this clear.
他上了你 往他的个人猎艳记录里加上一笔
He fucks you, gets footage for his redo wank file,
你却还和他很亲密！
but you're still pally.
这么说太糟糕了！
This is sad!
- 因为如果他 - 这一切太糟糕了！
- Cos if he was… - This is just sad!
他可能正坐在那里 盖着羊毛毯
He probably sits there and tosses himself.
愉快的打着他的小飞机
off all over his cashmere blanket.
这已经是很久以前的事了！
It was years ago!
对他来说可不是
Not for him.
然后我其实是在看
I'd find myself watching redos of really hot times.
我早年激情四射时的记忆回放
early in relationships.
淡定！
Easy.
清醒一点 去吐一下你就酒醒了！
Sober up. Make yourself puke.
或者顺便你要怎么做 我不管了
Whatever, I don't care. Just sort this out.
靠！
Fuck.
然后我其实是在看
I'd find myself watching redos of really hot times.
我早年激情四射时的记忆回放
early in relationships.
淡定！
Easy.
我却坐在楼下 回放那些激情时刻
And I'm downstairs watching some redo of some night.
和那些我都不知道在哪搭上的女孩的激情时刻
I've picked up somebody else and…
她就在楼上 等着和我缠绵
Yeah, nice, Geoff. She's upstairs waiting to have sex with me.
我却坐在楼下 回放那些激情时刻
and I'm downstairs watching some redo.
和那些我都不知道在哪搭上的女孩的激情时刻
of some night I've picked up somebody else.
淡定！
Easy.
我真是太圆满了！说真的 太圆满了
And I'm fucking pulling myself off. I'm just saying.
友情提醒
Green warning.
芯片助手提醒你 你现在的身体状况
Grain assistant suggests you may not be in a suitable.
不适合做现在的事
physical condition for the activity you appear to be engaged in.
如果置之不理的话 你会有生命危险
To override, continue at your own risk.
所以的健康和意外保险都
All health and personal accident insurance is…
真是谢谢你了
Thank you.
- 谁啊？- 利亚姆
- Who's that? - It's Liam.
我们昨晚刚见过
Liam from last night.
利亚姆 斐和你一起的吗？
Liam. Is Fi with you?
没有 没
She's not, no.
不好意思 但你有什么事吗？
Sorry, Liam, mate, is there something that you want?
是 我想和你谈谈
Yeah, I just want to come in and talk to you.
能把门打开吗？
Can you open the gate?
- 当然 - 进来吧
- Yeah, sure. - I'll let you in.
好的 太好了
Nice one, nice one.
你有什么事？
What do you want?
我就是想进来看看 兄弟
I just want to come in for a bit, dude.
这看起来很豪华 很贵吧？
That looks expensive. Is that expensive?
利亚姆 现在还是早上 兄弟
Look, Liam, it's morning, mate.
他妈的 利亚姆！
Fucking hell. Liam.
乔纳斯 这儿真漂亮
Jonas, this is a nice place!
说真的 你就这样走进来可不太好
Hey. Seriously, man, it's not cool you just walking in like this.
准确的说 是有点奇怪
To be honest with you, it's a little bit weird.
这是个马拉喀什台灯吗？
Is that a Marrakeshian lamp?
利亚姆 需要我打给斐吗？
Liam, do I have to call Fi?
你们吵架了还是怎么的？
Did you guys have a row or something like that?
- 坐下 - 不 我站着很好
- Sit down. - No, I'm all right.
快坐下吧 又不是有陷阱 只是把椅子
Go on, sit down. It's not a bear trap, it's a chair.
你想我用这个砸你的傻逼头吗？
Do you want me to bounce this off your fucking head?
我开玩笑的 琼斯
I'm joking, Jonas.
见鬼了 我觉得你应该对客人周到点
Bloody hell, I thought you were supposed to be cool, man.
我还以为你他妈是个高素质的人呢
I thought you were meant to be fucking brilliant.
怎么了？
What's going on?
需要一点图像
Yeah, figures.
需要点精彩图像粘贴到剪贴板上
Get some good stuff for the scrapbook?
你应该离开了
I think you should go.
我不会怪你的 虽然我本应该
I don't blame you. I would have.
我说 让我们看看
Tell you what, let's have a look.
来嘛 在这屏幕上放一下 别害羞！
Go on, chuck it on the screen, don't be shy!
来嘛
Come on!
我还是在开玩笑 乔纳斯
I'm fucking joking again, Jonas!
看在上帝份上 你应该具有点幽默感！
For goodness' sake, you need to grow a sense of humour.
- 他太死板了 是吧？- 行了 利亚姆
- He's uptight, isn't he? - OK, Liam.
- 这房间真可爱 这间 - 谢谢
- It's a lovely room, this. - Thank you.
你是在这对着我妻子的影像进行手淫？
Is this where you masturbate to images of my wife?
还是在那间房？
Or do you do it in that room?
好了 利亚姆 请你离开
OK, Liam, I want you to leave now.
还是说从这里开始
Do you sometimes start in here.
在那间结束？
and then finish in there?
你可以随性所欲 是不是？
The world's pretty much your oyster, isn't it?
请你离开
I want you to leave.
怎么喝完了
Well, that's a pity.
走吧 兄弟
Come on, mate.
好啊 你要干什么？
All right, now, what are you doing?
别这样 别这么做
Don't do that. Come on now!
- 你在干什么！- 你又在干什么！
- What are you doing? - What are you doing?
- 天哪 滚出去 - 站起来 乔纳斯 起来
- Jesus! Get out! - Stand up, Jonas, come on!
有什么事？
What do you want?
别这样
Don't do that.
来啊 丹尼
Come on, Danny!
- 你在干什么！- 你又在干什么
- What are you doing? - What are you doing?
滚出去 你他妈个二货
Jesus! Get out, you fucking prick.
我跟你说
Tell you what…
住手
Stop it!
我告诉你你一个要做些什么
I tell you what you're going to do.
把你脑海里每一帧关于斐的记忆
You're going to get every bit of Fion you've got in there.
都挑选出来！全部删除！
and you're going to select it all and you're going to wipe it!
警察局吗？这里有一起严重的斗殴事件
Hello, police, I'm witnessing a serious assault at five…
删除！
Wipe it!
滚你妈的
Fuck off.
我没有芯片 没法给你展现斗殴现场
I don't have a brain chip to show you.
这是一个瓶子 看见没？
This is a bottle, right?
要不你删掉
Either you wipe it…
要不我就从你脑子里挖出来
or I will fucking gouge you myself.
上帝！
Jesus!
好
OK.
照他说的做
Just do what he says.
别在你脑海里 放到那上面
Not on your eye, in there.
放到屏幕上！
On there!
他在做了
He's doing it!
现在 删除它 全部！
Now, delete it all. The lot!
不然我就打碎你脑袋 再割破你喉咙
Or I will crack your skull and I will gouge your fucking neck.
我正在删
I'm doing it.
离我妻子远点！
Stay away from my house!
现在 删除它 全部！
Now, delete it all. The lot!
不然我就打碎你脑袋 再割破你喉咙
Or I will crack your skull and I will gouge your fucking neck.
我正在删
I'm doing it.
利亚姆
Liam?
你去哪儿了？
Where did you go?
怎么了？
What happened?
利亚姆 怎么了？
Liam, what happened?
你用套了没？
Did you use a condom or not?
回答我
Just say.
利亚姆 无论你在想什么
Liam, whatever you think…
我是朱迪的爸爸吗？
Am I Jodie's father?
- 利亚姆 - 是我吗
- Liam! - Am I?
当然是！
Yes, of course.
- 你确定？- 是！
- You sure about that? - Yes!
很好
That's nice.
你一直喜欢那幅画 是吗？
I always liked that picture, didn't you?
所以我买下它送给你
It's why I bought it for you.
我不喜欢 它看起来像是自命不凡的胡扯
I never liked it. Thought it was pretentious shit.
我告诉你你需要要做些什么
I'll tell you what you're going to do.
把你脑海里每一帧有关于斐的记忆都
You're going to get every bit of Fion…
天啊 你都做了些什么？
Christ, what have you done?
都收集挑选出来
Select it all…
马上就要到最精彩的部分了
We're getting to the good bit.
警察局吗？这里有一起严重的斗殴事件
Hello, police, I'm witnessing a serious assault at…
现在 删除它 全部！
Now, delete it all. The lot!
不然就打碎你脑袋 再割破你喉咙
Or I will crack your skull and I will gouge your fucking neck.
18个月前 就在这个房间里
18 months ago in this room.
你知道吗 如果你怀疑一件事
You know when you suspect something,
当它被证明是真的的时候 反而感觉比较好
it's always better when it turns out to be true.
就像是 我有一颗烂了好几年的牙
It's like I've had a bad tooth for years and I'm just finally.
最后终于用舌头把里面烂掉的渣滓全弄出来了
getting my tongue in there and I'm digging out all the rotten shit.
这不是你想的那样
That's not what it looks like.
乔纳斯有没有来给你读过睡前故事？
This did Jonas come round to read you a story?
不 它只是
No, it was…
充满爱意的睡前故事？
A story about fucking?
它只是
It was…
上次丹的事发生的时候 你摔门而去
When all the Dan stuff was going on and you'd walked out.
就离开了10分钟
For like ten minutes.
你离开了5天！利亚姆
For five days, Liam.
没打来电话 什么都没有
No call, no nothing.
所以你和他搞了四天？
So you fucked him after four days?
你们真是太英勇了
That's heroic.
3天都够让人敬佩了！但你们搞了4天？
I mean, three days, that's admirable, but four days?
你们都粘在一起了吧
I mean, you must have been gagging.
我那时太伤心了
I was so upset.
我们去喝酒 我喝醉了
We went for a drink, I got drunk.
这一切本不应该发生的
It shouldn't have happened.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 除此之外我也不知道要说些什么
I'm so sorry, I can't say anything else.
我爱你
I love you.
你们戴套了吗？
Did you use a condom?
是的
Yes.
那时我们家没有 因为我们正试着要孩子
Cos we didn't have any here. We were trying.
他带了
He had some.
在他口袋里？
In his pocket?
在他车里
In his car.
他要戴 还是你让他戴的？
Was it his decision, or did you make him wear one?
我让他戴的
I made him.
- 你看见他戴上了？- 是的
- And you saw him put it on? - Yes.
那么 放出来给我看
Show me, then.
在那个屏幕上放出来
Show me on there.
我需要确认 斐
I need to see it, Fi.
我删了
I deleted it.
我想它烟消云散 我把一切都删了
I wanted it to go away, I wiped the whole thing.
- 是吗 - 是
- Did you? - Yeah.
那你的记忆时间轴里一定有一段空白
So there's just a blank gap in your timeline?
是
Yeah.
把那个放给我看
Show me that, then.
好
Yeah, OK.
我要先找出它
I have to find it.
不 别现在再删！
No! No deleting it, not now.
不要 不要
No, no.
它还在 是不是？
It's still on there, is it?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你需要放给我看 斐
You have to show it to me, Fi.
为什么
Why?
因为我想要看一下
Cos I want to see it.
我爱你
I love you.
放给我看
Show it to me.
不
No.
- 放给我看 - 不
- Show it to me. - No.
- Show it to me! - No!
放给我看 我要看
Show it to me! I want to see!
看他到底怎么做的！
I want to see what he looks like!
我都不像自己了
This isn't me!
看看你把我变成了什么样！
Look what you're doing to me!
斐 我要看
Fi, I need to see it!
求你了
Please.
我要看 斐
I need to see it, Fi.
- 快一点 - 不好意思！
- Hurry up. - Sorry!
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I know you do.
你好 小臭臭
Hello, stinky!
棕色还是绿色？
Brown or green?
绿色
Green?